<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cards>
  <spells>
    <spell>
      <name>Animate Dead</name>
      <type>3rd-level necromancy</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 minute</castingTime>
      <range>10 feet</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a drop of blood, a piece of flesh, and a pinch of bone dust</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        Erhebt Knochen zu einem Skelet oder ein Leichnam zu einem Zombie. In jeder Runde kann per Bonus Aktion einen Befehl gegeben werden.
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel>
        Für jeden Level über dem 3. kann ein zusätzlicher Untote erhoben werden.
      </atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        This spell creates an undead servant. Choose a pile of bones or a corpse of a Medium or Small humanoid within range. Your spell imbues the target with a foul mimicry of life, raising it as an undead creature. The target becomes a skeleton if you chose bones or a zombie if you chose a corpse (the DM has the creature’s game statistics).<br/>
        On each of your turns, you can use a bonus action to mentally command any creature you made with this spell if the creature is within 60 feet of you (if you control multiple creatures, you can command any or all of them at the same time, issuing the same command to each one). You decide what action the creature will take and where it will move during its next turn, or you can issue a general command, such as to guard a particular chamber or corridor. If you issue no commands, the creature only defends itself against hostile creatures. Once given an order, the creature continues to follow it until its task is complete.<br/>
        The creature is under your control for 24 hours, after which it stops obeying any command you’ve given it. To maintain control of the creature for another 24 hours, you must cast this spell on the creature again before the current 24-hour period ends. This use of the spell reasserts your control over up to four creatures you have animated with this spell, rather than animating a new one.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you animate or reassert control over two additional undead creatures for each slot level above 3rd. Each of the creatures must come from a different corpse or pile of bones.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Animate Objects</name>
      <type>5th-level transmutation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>120 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        Objects come to life at your command. Choose up to ten nonmagical objects within range that are not being worn or carried. Medium targets count as two objects, Large targets count as four objects, Huge targets count as eight objects. You can’t animate any object larger than Huge. Each target animates and becomes a creature under your control until the spell ends or until reduced to 0 hit points.<br/>
        As a bonus action, you can mentally command any creature you made with this spell if the creature is within 500 feet of you (if you control multiple creatures, you can command any or all of them at the same time, issuing the same command to each one). You decide what action the creature will take and where it will move during its next turn, or you can issue a general command, such as to guard a particular chamber or corridor. Ifyou issue no commands, the creature only defends itself against hostile creatures. Once given an order, the creature continues to follow it until its task is complete.<br/>

        are 3, and its Charisma is 1. Its speed is 30 feet; if the object lacks legs or other appendages it can use for locomotion, it instead has a flying speed of 30 feet and can hover. If the object is securely attached to a surface or a larger object, such as a chain bolted to a wall, its speed is 0. It has blindsight with a radius of 30 feet and is blind beyond that distance. When the animated object drops to 0 hit points, it reverts to its original object form, and any remaining damage carries over to its original object form.<br/>
        If you command an object to attack, it can make a single melee attack against a creature within 5 feet of it. It makes a slam attack with an attack bonus and bludgeoning damage determined by its size. The DM might rule that a specific object inflicts slashing or piercing damage based on its form.
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> Ifyou cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, you can animate two additional objects for each slot level above 5th.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Antilife Shell</name>
      <type>5th-level abjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Druid</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Self (10-foot radius)</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        A shimmering barrier extends out from you in a 10-foot radius and moves with you, remaining centered on you and hedging out creatures other than undead and constructs. The barrier lasts for the duration.<br/>
        The barrier prevents an affected creature from passing or reaching through. An affected creature can cast spells or make attacks with ranged or reach weapons through the barrier.<br/>
        If you move so that an affected creature is forced to pass through the barrier, the spell ends.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Bane</name>
      <type>1st-level enchantment</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Cleric</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>30 feet (sight)</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a drop of blood)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        Bis drei Ziele im Sichtfeld müssen einen Charisma-Rettungswurf bestehen. Bei Misslingen muss das Ziel bei jedem Angriffs- oder Rettungswurf einen d4 abziehen.
        Für jedes zusätzliche Level ein zusätzliches Ziel.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        Up to three creatures of your choice that you can see within range must make Charisma saving throws. Whenever a target that fails this saving throw makes an attack roll or a saving throw before the spell ends, the target must roll a d4 and subtract the number rolled from the attack roll or saving throw.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Beacon of Hope</name>
      <type>3rd-level abjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>30 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        This spell bestows hope and vitality. Choose any number of creatures within range. For the duration, each target has advantage on Wisdom saving throws and death saving throws, and regains the maximum number of hit points possible from any healing.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Bestow Curse</name>
      <type>3rd-level necromancy</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        Das berührte Wesen muss einen Weisheits-Rettungswurf bestehen oder wird verflucht von einer der folgenden Optionen:
        <ul>
          <li>Eine Eigenschaft wählen: Nachteil auf allen Eigenschaftsproben oder Rettungswürfen mit dieser Eigenschaft.</li>
          <li>Nachteil auf Attackwürfen.</li>
          <li>Weisheits-Rettungswurf bestehen zu Beginn jedes Zuges oder Aktionen sind verloren</li>
          <li>Deine Angriffe und Sprüche gegen dieses Wesen verursachen zusätzliche 1d8 necrotic Schaden.</li>
        </ul>
        Der <i>Remove Curse</i> Spruch beendet den Effekt.
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel>4: bis 10min, 5: bis 8h, 7: bis 24h, 9: bis dispelled, über 5. brauchen keine Concentration.</atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        You touch a creature, and that creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the duration of the spell. When you cast this spell, choose the nature of the curse from the following options:
        <ul>
          <li>Choose one ability score. While cursed, the target has disadvantage on ability checks and saving throws made with that ability score.</li>
          <li>While cursed, the target has disadvantage on attack rolls against you.</li>
          <li>While cursed, the target must make a Wisdom saving throw at the start of each of its turns. If it fails, it wastes its action that turn doing nothing.</li>
          <li>While the target is cursed, your attacks and spells deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage to the target.</li>
        </ul>
        A <i>remove curse</i> spell ends this effect. At the DM’s option, you may choose an alternative curse effect, but it should be no more powerful than those described above. The DM has final say on such a curse’s effect.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the duration is concentration, up to 10 minutes. If you use a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the duration is 8 hours. If you use a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the duration is 24 hours. If you use a 9th level spell slot, the spell lasts until it is dispelled. Using a spell slot of 5th level or higher grants a duration that doesn’t require concentration.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Bless</name>
      <type>1st-level enchantment</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Paladin</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>30 feet</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a sprinkling of holy water)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        Bis zu drei Wesen erhalten: Füge zu allen Angriffs- und Rettungswürfen einen d4 hinzu.
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel>Pro Level ein zusätzliches Wesen.</atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        You bless up to three creatures of your choice within range. Whenever a target makes an attack roll or a saving throw before the spell ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the attack roll or saving throw.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Blight</name>
      <type>4th-level necromancy</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Druid</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>30 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        Wesen muss ein Konstitutions-Rettungswurf machen und nimmt 8d8 necrotic Schaden bei einem Misserfolg und halb so viel bei einem erfolgreichen. Hat keinen Effekt bei Untoten oder Konstrukten.<br/>
        Planzenwesen oder magischen Pflanzen haben Nachteil auf dem Rettungswurf und nichtmagische Pflanzen versagen automatisch und sterben.
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        Necromantic energy washes over a creature of your choice that you can see within range, draining moisture and vitality from it. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. The target takes 8d8 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.<br/>
        If you target a plant creature or a magical plant, it makes the saving throw with disadvantage, and the spell deals maximum damage to it.<br/>
        If you target a nonmagical plant that isn’t a creature, such as a tree or shrub, it doesn’t make a saving throw; it simply withers and dies.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Blinding Smite</name>
      <type>3rd-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Paladin</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 bonus action</castingTime>
      <range>Self</range>
      <components>V</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        The next time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack during this spell’s duration, your weapon flares with bright light, and the attack deals an extra 3d8 radiant damage to the target. Additionally, the target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the spell ends.<br/>
        A creature blinded by this spell makes another Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a successful save, it is no longer blinded.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Blink</name>
      <type>3rd-level transmutation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Self</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        Roll a d20 at the end of each of your turns for the duration of the spell. On a roll of 11 or higher, you vanish from your current plane of existence and appear in the Ethereal Plane (the spell fails and the casting is wasted if you were already on that plane). At the start of your next turn, and when the spell ends if you are on the Ethereal Plane, you return to an unoccupied space of your choice that you can see within 10 feet of the space you vanished from. If no unoccupied space is available within that range, you appear in the nearest unoccupied space (chosen at random if more than one space is equally near). You can dismiss this spell as an action.<br/>
        While on the Ethereal Plane, you can see and hear the plane you originated from, which is cast in shades of gray, and you can’t see anything there more than 60 feet away. You can only affect and be affected by other creatures on the Ethereal Plane. Creatures that aren’t there can’t perceive you or interact with you, unless they have the ability to do so.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Blur</name>
      <type>2nd-level illusion</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Self</range>
      <components>V</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        Your body becomes blurred, shifting and wavering to all who can see you. For the duration, any creature has disadvantage on attack rolls against you. An attacker is immune to this effect if it doesn’t rely on sight, as with blindsight, or can see through illusions, as with truesight.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Call Lightning</name>
      <type>3rd-level conjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Druid</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>120 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        A storm cloud appears in the shape of a cylinder that is 10 feet tall with a 60-foot radius, centered on a point you can see 100 feet directly above you. The spell fails if you can’t see a point in the air where the storm cloud could appear (for example, if you are in a room that can’t accommodate the cloud).<br/>
        When you cast the spell, choose a point you can see within range. A bolt of lightning flashes down from the cloud to that point. Each creature within 5 feet of that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d10 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. On each of your turns until the spell ends, you can use your action to call down lightning in this way again, targeting the same point or a different one.<br/>
        If you are outdoors in stormy conditions when you cast this spell, the spell gives you control over the existing storm instead of creating a new one. Under such conditions, the spell’s damage increases by 1d10.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th or higher level, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 3rd.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Chill Touch</name>
      <type>Necromancy cantrip</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>120 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>1 round</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        Du erstellst eine geisterhafte Skeletthand im Bereich eines Wesens innhalb der Reichweite. Mach eine Fernkampfattacke gegen dieses Wesen um es mit Grabeskälte anzufallen. Bei einem Treffer nimmt das Ziel 1d8 necrotic Schaden, welches es nicht zurückerhalten kann bis zu Beginn deines nächsten Zuges. Bis dann hängt die Hand am Ziel.<br/>
        Der Schaden dieses Spruchs nimmt um 1d9 zu beim erreichen vom 5. Level (2d8), 11. Level (3d8) und 17. Level (4d8).
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        You create a ghostly, skeletal hand in the space of a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the creature to assail it with the chill of the grave. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 necrotic damage, and it can’t regain hit points until the start of your next turn. Until then, the hand clings to the target.<br/>
        If you hit an undead target, it also has disadvantage on attack rolls against you until the end of your next turn.<br/>
        This spell’s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Circle of Death</name>
      <type>6th-level necromancy</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>150 feet</range>
      <components>V, S, M (the powder of a crushed black pearl worth at least 500gp)</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        A sphere of negative energy ripples out in a 60-foot- radius sphere from a point within range. Each creature in that area must make a Constitution saving throw. A target takes 8d6 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases by 2d6 for each slot level above 6th.</atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        A sphere of negative energy ripples out in a 60-foot- radius sphere from a point within range. Each creature in that area must make a Constitution saving throw. A target takes 8d6 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
        <b>At Higher Levels</b>. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases by 2d6 for each slot level above 6th.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Cone of Cold</name>
      <type>5th-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Self (60ft cone)</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a small crystal or glass cone)</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        A blast of cold air erupts from your hands. Each creature in a 60-foot cone must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 8d8 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.<br/>
        A creature killed by this spell becomes a frozen statue until it thaws.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 5th.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Confusion</name>
      <type>4th-level enchantment</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Druid</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>90 feet</range>
      <components>V, S, M (three nut shells)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        This spell assaults and twists creatures' minds, spawning delusions and provoking uncontrolled action. Each creature in a 10-foot-radius sphere centered on a point you choose within range must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw when you cast this spell or be affected by it.<br/>
        An affected target can’t take reactions and must roll a d10 at the start of each of its turns to determine its behavior for that turn.
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>d10</th>
            <th>Behaviour</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>1</td>
            <td>The creature uses all its movement to move in a random direction. To determine the direction, roll a d8 and assign a direction to each die face. The creature doesn’t take an action this turn.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2-6</td>
            <td>The creature doesn’t move or take actions this turn.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>7-8</td>
            <td>The creature uses its action to make a melee attack against a randomly determined creature within its reach. Ifthere is no creature within its reach, the creature does nothing this turn.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>9-10</td>
            <td>The creature can act and move normally.</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        At the end of each of its turns, an affected target can make a Wisdom saving throw. If it succeeds, this effect ends for that target.
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the radius of the sphere increases by 5 feet for each slot level above 4th.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Contagion</name>
      <type>5th-level necromancy</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Druid</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>7 days</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        Your touch inflicts disease. Make a melee spell attack against a creature within your reach. On a hit, you afflict the creature with a disease of your choice from any of the ones described below.<br/>
        At the end of each of the target’s turns, it must make a Constitution saving throw. After failing three of these saving throws, the disease’s effects last for the duration, and the creature stops making these saves. After succeeding on three of these saving throws, the creature recovers from the disease, and the spell ends.<br/>
        Since this spell induces a natural disease in its target, any effect that removes a disease or otherwise ameliorates a disease’s effects apply to it.<br/>
        <b>Blinding Sickness.</b> Pain grips the creature’s mind, and its eyes turn milky white. The creature has disadvantage on W isdom checks and W isdom saving throws and is blinded.<br/>
        <b>Filth Fever.</b> A raging fever sweeps through the creature’s body. The creature has disadvantage on Strength checks, Strength saving throws, and attack rolls that use Strength.<br/>
        <b>Flesh Rot.</b> The creature’s flesh decays. The creature has disadvantage on Charisma checks and vulnerability to all damage.<br/>
        <b>Mindfire.</b> The creature’s mind becom es feverish. The creature has disadvantage on Intelligence checks and Intelligence saving throws, and the creature behaves as if under the effects of the confusion spell during combat.<br/>
        <b>Seizure.</b> The creature is overcome with shaking. The creature has disadvantage on Dexterity checks, Dexterity saving throws, and attack rolls that use Dexterity.<br/>
        <b>Slimy Doom.</b> The creature begins to bleed uncontrollably. The creature has disadvantage on Constitution checks and Constitution saving throws. In addition, whenever the creature takes damage, it is stunned until the end of its next turn.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Counterspell</name>
      <type>3rd-level abjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 reaction, when you see a creature within 60 feet of you casting a spell</castingTime>
      <range>60 feet</range>
      <components>S</components>
      <duration>Inst</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        You attempt to interrupt a creature in the process of casting a spell. If the creature is casting a spell of 3rd level or lower, its spell fails and has no effect. If it is casting a spell of 4th level or higher, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level. On a success, the creature’s spell fails and has no effect.
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the interrupted spell has no effect if its level is less than or equal to the level of the spell slot you used.</atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        You attempt to interrupt a creature in the process of casting a spell. If the creature is casting a spell of 3rd level or lower, its spell fails and has no effect. If it is casting a spell of 4th level or higher, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level. On a success, the creature’s spell fails and has no effect.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the interrupted spell has no effect if its level is less than or equal to the level of the spell slot you used.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Create Undead</name>
      <type>6th-level necromancy</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 minute</castingTime>
      <range>10 feet</range>
      <components>V, S, M (one clay pot filled with grave dirt, one clay pot filled with brackish water, and one 150gp black onyx stone for each corpse)</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        You can cast this spell only at night. Choose up to three corpses of Medium or Small humanoids within range. Each corpse becomes a ghoul under your control. (The DM has game statistics for these creatures.)<br/>
        As a bonus action on each of your turns, you can mentally command any creature you animated with this spell if the creature is within 120 feet of you (if you control multiple creatures, you can command any or all of them at the same time, issuing the same command to each one). You decide what action the creature will take and where it will move during its next turn, or you can issue a general command, such as to guard a particular chamber or corridor. If you issue no commands, the creature only defends itself against hostile creatures. Once given an order, the creature continues to follow it until its task is complete.<br/>
        The creature is under your control for 24 hours, after which it stops obeying any command you have given it. To maintain control of the creature for another 24 hours, you must cast this spell on the creature before the current 24-hour period ends. This use of the spell reasserts your control over up to three creatures you have animated with this spell, rather than animating new ones.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a 7th-level spell slot, you can animate or reassert control over four ghouls. When you cast this spell using an 8th-level spell slot, you can animate or reassert control over five ghouls or two ghasts or wights. When you cast this spell using a 9th-level spell slot, you can animate or reassert control over six ghouls, three ghasts or wights, or two mummies.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Cure Wounds</name>
      <type>1st-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Druid</class>
        <class>Paladin</class>
        <class>Ranger</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        A creature you touch regains a number of hit points equal to 1d8 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Dispel Magic</name>
      <type>3rd-level abjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Druid</class>
        <class>Paladin</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>120 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        Choose one creature, object, or magical effect within range. Any spell of 3rd level or lower on the target ends. For each spell of 4th level or higher on the target, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level. On a successful check, the spell ends.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you automatically end the effects of a spell on the target if the spell’s level is equal to or less than the level of the spell slot you used.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>False Life</name>
      <type>1st-level necromancy</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Paladin</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Self</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a small amount of alcohol or distilled spirits)</components>
      <duration>1 hour</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        Bolstering yourself with a necromantic facsimile of life, you gain 1d4 + 4 temporary hit points for the duration.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you gain 5 additional temporary hit points for each slot level above 1st.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Fear</name>
      <type>3rd-level illusion</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Self (30-feet cone)</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a white feather or the heart of a hen)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        You project a phantasmal image of a creature’s worst fears. Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a W isdom saving throw or drop whatever it is holding and become frightened for the duration.<br/>
        While frightened by this spell, a creature must take the Dash action and move away from you by the safest available route on each of its turns, unless there is nowhere to move. If the creature ends its turn in a location where it doesn’t have line of sight to you, the creature can make a W isdom saving throw. On a successful save, the spell ends for that creature.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Fireball</name>
      <type>3rd-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>150 feet</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a tiny ball of bat guano and sulfur)</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        A bright streak flashes from your pointing finger to a point you choose within range and then blossoms with a low roar into an explosion of flame. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 8d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.<br/>
        The fire spreads around corners. It ignites flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Fire Bolt</name>
      <type>Evocation cantrip</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>120 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription></shortDescription>
      <description>
        You hurl a mote of fire at a creature or object within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 fire damage. A flammable object hit by this spell ignites if it isn't being worn or carried.<br/>
        This spell’s damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Fire Shield</name>
      <type>4th-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Self</range>
      <components>V, S, M (bit of phosphorus)</components>
      <duration>10 minutes</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        Eine dünne Flammen- oder Eisschicht überzieht den Körper. Sobald eine Kreature innerhalb von 1,5m eine Nahkampfattacke macht, erhält dieser 2d8 fire bzw cold Schaden. Zusätzlich erhälst du Resistenz gegen cold Schaden beim Feuerschild bzw gegen fire Schaden beim Eisschild.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        Thin and wispy flames wreathe your body for the duration, shedding bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. You can end the spell early by using an action to dismiss it.<br/>
        The flames provide you with a warm shield or a chill shield, as you choose. The warm shield grants you resistance to cold damage, and the chill shield grants you resistance to fire damage.<br/>
        In addition, whenever a creature within 5 feet of you hits you with a melee attack, the shield erupts with flame. The attacker takes 2d8 fire damage from a warm shield, or 2d8 cold damage from a cold shield.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Flaming Sphere</name>
      <type>2nd-level conjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Druid</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>60 feet</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a bit of tallow, a pinch of brimstone, and a dusting of powdered iron)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        A 5-foot-diameter sphere of fire appears in an unoccupied space of your choice within range and lasts for the duration. Any creature that ends its turn within 5 feet of the sphere must make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 2d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.<br/>
        As a bonus action, you can move the sphere up to 30 feet. If you ram the sphere into a creature, that creature must make the saving throw against the sphere’s damage, and the sphere stops moving this turn.<br/>
        When you move the sphere, you can direct it over barriers up to 5 feet tall and jump it across pits up to 10 feet wide. The sphere ignites flammable objects not being worn or carried, and it sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Fly</name>
      <type>3rd-level transmutation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a wing feather from any bird)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        You touch a willing creature. The target gains a flying speed of 60 feet for the duration. When the spell ends, the target falls if it is still aloft, unless it can stop the fall.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 3rd.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Globe of Invulnerability</name>
      <type>6th-level abjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Self (10 foot radius)</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a glass or crystal bead that shatters when the spell ends)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        An immobile, faintly shimmering barrier springs into existence in a 10-foot radius around you and remains for the duration.<br/>
        Any spell of 5th level or lower cast from outside the barrier can't affect creatures or objects within it, even if the spell is cast using a higher level spell slot. Such a spell can target creatures and objects within the barrier, but the spell has no effect on them. Similarly, the area within the barrier is excluded from the areas affected by such spells.<br/>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the barrier blocks spells of one level higher for each slot level above 6th.</atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        An immobile, faintly shimmering barrier springs into existence in a 10-foot radius around you and remains for the duration.<br/>
        Any spell of 5th level or lower cast from outside the barrier can't affect creatures or objects within it, even if the spell is cast using a higher level spell slot. Such a spell can target creatures and objects within the barrier, but the spell has no effect on them. Similarly, the area within the barrier is excluded from the areas affected by such spells.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the barrier blocks spells of one level higher for each slot level above 6th.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Greater Invisibility</name>
      <type>4th-level illusion</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        You or a creature you touch becomes invisible until the spell ends. Anything the target is wearing or carrying is invisible as long as it is on the target’s person.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Guiding Bolt</name>
      <type>1st-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>120 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>1 round</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        A flash of light streaks toward a creature of your choice within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 4d6 radiant damage, and the next attack roll made against this target before the end of your next turn has advantage, thanks to the mystical dim light glittering on the target until then.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Harm</name>
      <type>6th-level necromancy</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>60 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        You unleash a virulent disease on a creature that you can see within range. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 14d6 necrotic damage, or half as much damage on a successful save. The damage can’t reduce the target’s hit points below 1. If the target fails the saving throw, its hit point maximum is reduced for 1 hour by an amount equal to the necrotic damage it took. Any effect that removes a disease allows a creature’s hit point maximum to return to normal before that time passes.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Healing Word</name>
      <type>1st-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Druid</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 bonus action</castingTime>
      <range>60 feet</range>
      <components>V</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        A creature of your choice that you can see within range regains hit points equal to 1d4 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Hold Person</name>
      <type>2nd-level enchantment</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Druid</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>60 feet</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a small, straight piece of iron)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        Choose a humanoid that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a W isdom saving throw or be paralyzed for the duration. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Wisdom saving throw. On a success, the spell ends on the target.
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel>
        When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional humanoid for each slot level above 2nd. The humanoids must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.
      </atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        Choose a humanoid that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a W isdom saving throw or be paralyzed for the duration. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Wisdom saving throw. On a success, the spell ends on the target.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional humanoid for each slot level above 2nd. The humanoids must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Hypnotic Pattern</name>
      <type>3rd-level illusion</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>120 feet</range>
      <components>S, M (a glowing stick of incense or a crystal vial filled with phosphorescent material)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        You create a twisting pattern of colors that weaves through the air inside a 30-foot cube within range. The pattern appears for a moment and vanishes. Each creature in the area who sees the pattern must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature becomes charmed for the duration. While charmed by this spell, the creature is incapacitated and has a speed of 0.<br/>
        The spell ends for an affected creature if it takes any damage or if someone else uses an action to shake the creature out of its stupor.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Ice Storm</name>
      <type>4th-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Druid</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>300 feet</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a pinch of dust and a few drops of water)</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        A hail of rock-hard ice pounds to the ground in a 20-foot-radius, 40-foot-high cylinder centered on a point within range. Each creature in the cylinder must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 2d8 bludgeoning damage and 4d6 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.<br/>
        Hailstones turn the storm's area of effect into difficult terrain until the end of your next turn.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the bludgeoning damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Lesser Restoration</name>
      <type>2nd-level abjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Druid</class>
        <class>Paladin</class>
        <class>Ranger</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        You touch a creature and can end either one disease or one condition afflicting it. The condition can be blinded, deafened, paralyzed, or poisoned.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Light</name>
      <type>Evocation cantrip</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, M (a firefly of phosphorescent moss)</components>
      <duration>1 hour</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        You touch one object that is no larger than 10 feet in any dimension. Until the spell ends, the object sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. The light can be colored as you like. Completely covering the object with something opaque blocks the light. The spell ends if you cast it again or dismiss it as an action.<br/>
        If you target an object held or worn by a hostile creature, that creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw to avoid the spell.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Lightning Bolt</name>
      <type>3rd-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Self (100ft line)</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a bit of fur and a rod of amber)</components>
      <duration>Inst</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        Blitzschlag 33m weit und 1,5 m breit. Alle Kreaturen in dieser Linie müssen einen Dex-Rettungswurf machen. Fehlgeschlagen nehmen sie 8d6 blitz-Schaden oder halb soviel.<br/>
        Entflammbare Objekte in dieser Linie entzünden sich.<br/>
        Für jeden höheren Level +1d6
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Mage Armor</name>
      <type>1st-level abjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a piece of cured leather)</components>
      <duration>8 hours</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        You touch a willing creature who isn’t wearing armor, and a protective magical force surrounds it until the spell ends.The target’s base AC becomes 13+ its Dexterity modifier. The spell ends if the target dons armor or ifyou dismiss the spell as an action.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Mage Hand</name>
      <type>Conjuration cantrip</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>30 ft</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        A spectral, floating hand appears at a point you choose within range. The hand lasts for the duration or until you dismiss it as an action. The hand vanishes if it is ever m ore than 30 feet away from you or if you cast this spell again.<br/>
        You can use your action to control the hand. You can use the hand to manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an item from an open container, or pour the contents out of a vial. You can move the hand up to 30 feet each time you use it.<br/>
        The hand can’t attack, activate magic items, or carry more than 10 pounds.<br/>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Magic Missile</name>
      <type>1st-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>120 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        You create three glowing darts of magical force. Each dart hits a creature of your choice that you can see within range. A dart deals 1d4 + 1 force damage to its target. The darts all strike simultaneously, and you can direct them to hit one creature or several.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the spell creates one more dart for each slot level above 1st.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Mass Healing Word</name>
      <type>3rd-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 bonus action</castingTime>
      <range>60 feet</range>
      <components>V</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        As you call out words of restoration, up to six creatures of your choice that you can see within range regain hit points equal to 1d4 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 3rd.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Minor Illusion</name>
      <type>Illusion cantrip</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>30 feet</range>
      <components>S, M (a bit of fleece)</components>
      <duration>1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        You create a sound or an image of an object within range that lasts for the duration. The illusion also ends if you dismiss it as an action or cast this spell again.<br/>
        If you create a sound, its volume can range from a whisper to a scream. It can be your voice, someone else’s voice, a lion’s roar, a beating of drums, or any other sound you choose. The sound continues unabated throughout the duration, or you can make discrete sounds at different times before the spell ends.<br/>
        If you create an image of an object—such as a chair, muddy footprints, or a small chest—it must be no larger than a 5-foot cube. The image can’t create sound, light, smell, or any other sensory effect. Physical interaction with the image reveals it to be an illusion, because things can pass through it.<br/>
        If a creature uses its action to examine the sound or image, the creature can determine that it is an illusion with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the illusion becomes faint to the creature.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Mirror Image</name>
      <type>2nd-level illusion</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Self</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        Three illusory duplicates of yourself appear in your space. Until the spell ends, the duplicates move with you and mimic your actions, shifting position so it’s impossible to track which image is real. You can use your action to dismiss the illusory duplicates.<br/>
        Each time a creature targets you with an attack during the spell’s duration, roll a d20 to determine whether the attack instead targets one of your duplicates.<br/>
        If you have three duplicates, you must roll a 6 or higher to change the attack’s target to a duplicate. With two duplicates, you must roll an 8 or higher. With one duplicate, you must roll an 11 or higher.<br/>
        A duplicate’s AC equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier. If an attack hits a duplicate, the duplicate is destroyed. A duplicate can be destroyed only by an attack that hits it. It ignores all other damage and effects. The spell ends when all three duplicates are destroyed.<br/>
        A creature is unaffected by this spell if it can’t see, if it relies on senses other than sight, such as blindsight, or if it can perceive illusions as false, as with truesight.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Misty Step</name>
      <type>2nd-level conjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 bonus action</castingTime>
      <range>Self</range>
      <components>V</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        Briefly surrounded by silvery mist, you teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Phantasmal Killer</name>
      <type>4th-level illusion</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>120 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        You tap into the nightmares of a creature you can see within range and create an illusory manifestation of its deepest fears, visible only to that creature. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target becomes frightened for the duration. At the start of each of the target’s turns before the spell ends, the target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or take 4d10 psychic damage. On a successful save, the spell ends.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 4th.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Prayer of Healing</name>
      <type>2nd-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>10 minutes</castingTime>
      <range>30 feet</range>
      <components>V</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        Up to six creatures of your choice that you can see within range each regain hit points equal to 2d8 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Prestidigitation</name>
      <type>Transmutation cantrip</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>10 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Up to 1 hour</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        This spell is a minor magical trick that novice spellcasters use for practice. You create one of the following magical effects within range:<br/>
        <ul>
          <li>You create an instantaneous, harmless sensory effect, such as a shower of sparks, a puff of wind, faint musi cal notes, or an odd odor.</li>
          <li>You instantaneously light or snuff out a candle, a torch, or a small campfire.</li>
          <li>You instantaneously clean or soil an object no larger than 1 cubic foot.</li>
          <li>You chill, warm, or flavor up to 1 cubic foot of nonliv ing material for 1 hour.</li>
          <li>You make a color, a small mark, or a symbol appear on an object or a surface for 1 hour.</li>
          <li>You create a nonmagical trinket or an illusory image that can fit in your hand and that lasts until the end of your next turn.</li>
        </ul>
        If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its non-instantaneous effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Protection from Energy</name>
      <type>3rd-level abjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Druid</class>
        <class>Ranger</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        For the duration, the willing creature you touch has resistance to one damage type of your choice: acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Ray of Enfeeblement</name>
      <type>2nd-level necromancy</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>60 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Concentration</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        A black beam of enervating energy springs from your finger toward a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target deals only half damage with weapon attacks that use Strength until the spell ends.<br/>w
        At the end of each of the target’s turns, it can make a Constitution saving throw against the spell. On a success, the spell ends.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Ray of Sickness</name>
      <type>1st-level necromancy</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>60 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        A ray of sickening greenish energy lashes out toward a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 poison damage and must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it is also poisoned until the end of your next turn.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Resistance</name>
      <type>Abjuration cantrip</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Druid</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a miniature cloak)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        You touch one willing creature. Once before the spell ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to one saving throw of its choice. It can roll the die before or after making the saving throw. The spell then ends.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Revivify</name>
      <type>3rd-level conjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Paladin</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, S, M (diamonds worth 300gp, which the spell consumes)</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        You touch a creature that has died within the last minute. That creature returns to life with 1 hit point. This spell can’t return to life a creature that has died of old age, nor can it restore any missing body parts.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Sacred Flame</name>
      <type>Evocation cantrip</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>60 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        Flame-like radiance descends on a creature that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d8 radiant damage. The target gains no benefit from cover for this saving throw.<br/>
        The spell’s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Sanctuary</name>
      <type>1st-level abjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 bonus action</castingTime>
      <range>30 feet</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a small silver mirror)</components>
      <duration>1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        You ward a creature within range against attack. Until the spell ends, any creature who targets the warded creature with an attack or a harmful spell must first make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature must choose a new target or lose the attack or spell. This spell doesn’t protect the warded creature from area effects, such as the explosion of a fireball.<br/>
        If the warded creature makes an attack or casts a spell that affects an enemy creature, this spell ends.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Shield</name>
      <type>1st-level abjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 reaction, which you take when you are hit by an attack or targeted by the <i>magic missile</i> spell</castingTime>
      <range>Self</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>1 round</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        An invisible barrier of magical force appears and protects you. Until the start of your next turn, you have a +5 bonus to AC, including against the triggering attack, and you take no damage from magic missile.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Shocking Grasp</name>
      <type>Evocation cantrip</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        Lightning springs from your hand to deliver a shock to a creature you try to touch. Make a melee spell attack against the target. You have advantage on the attack roll if the target is wearing armor made of metal. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 lightning damage, and it can’t take reactions until the start of its next turn.<br/>
        The spell’s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Spirit Guardians</name>
      <type>3rd-level conjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Self (15-foot radius)</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a holy symbol)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        You call forth spirits to protect you. They flit around you to a distance of 15 feet for the duration. If you are good or neutral, their spectral form appears angelic or fey (your choice). If you are evil, they appear fiendish.<br/>
        When you cast this spell, you can designate any number of creatures you can see to be unaffected by it. An affected creature’s speed is halved in the area, and when the creature enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 3d8 radiant damage (if you are good or neutral) or 3d8 necrotic damage (if you are evil). On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 3rd.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Spiritual Weapon</name>
      <type>2nd-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 bonus action</castingTime>
      <range>60 feet</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        You create a floating, spectral weapon within range that lasts for the duration or until you cast this spell again. When you cast the spell, you can make a melee spell attack against a creature within 5 feet of the weapon. On a hit, the target takes force damage equal to 1d8 + your spellcasting ability modifier.<br/>
        As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the weapon up to 20 feet and repeat the attack against a creature within 5 feet of it.<br/>
        The weapon can take whatever form you choose. Clerics of deities who are associated with a particular weapon (as St. Cuthbert is known for his mace and Thor for his hammer) make this spell’s effect resemble that weapon.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for every two slot levels above the 2nd.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Stoneskin</name>
      <type>4th-level abjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Druid</class>
        <class>Ranger</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Touch</range>
      <components>V, S, M (diamond dust worth 100gp, which the spell consumes)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
      <shortDescription>
        This spell turns the flesh of a willing creature you touch as hard as stone. Until the spell ends, the target has resistance to nonmagical bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Suggestion</name>
      <type>2nd-level enchantment</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>30 feet</range>
      <components>V, M (a snake's</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 8 hours</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        You suggest a course of activity (limited to a sentence or two) and magically influence a creature you can see within range that can hear and understand you. Creatures that can’t be charmed are immune to this effect. The suggestion must be worded in such a manner as to make the course of action sound reasonable. Asking the creature to stab itself, throw itself onto a spear, immolate itself, or do some other obviously harmful act ends the spell.<br/>
        The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, it pursues the course of action you described to the best of its ability. The suggested course of action can continue for the entire duration. If the suggested activity can be completed in a shorter time, the spell ends when the subject finishes what it was asked to do.<br/>
        You can also specify conditions that will trigger a special activity during the duration. For example, you might suggest that a knight give her warhorse to the first beggar she meets. If the condition isn’t met before the spell expires, the activity isn’t performed.<br/>
        If you or any of your companions damage the target, the spell ends.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Teleport</name>
      <type>7th-level conjuration</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Bard</class>
        <class>Sorcerer</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>10 feet</range>
      <components>V</components>
      <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Thaumaturgy</name>
      <type>Transmutation cantrip</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Cleric</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>30 feet</range>
      <components>V</components>
      <duration>Up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        You manifest a minor wonder, a sign of supernatural power, within range. You create one of the following magical effects within range:
        <ul>
          <li>Your voice booms up to three times as loud as normal for 1 minute.</li>
          <li>You cause flames to flicker, brighten, dim, or change color for 1 minute.</li>
          <li>You cause harmless tremors in the ground for 1 minute.</li>
          <li>You create an instantaneous sound that originates from a point of your choice within range, such as a rumble of thunder, the cry of a raven, or ominous whispers.</li>
          <li>You instantaneously cause an unlocked door or win dow to fly open or slam shut.</li>
          <li>You alter the appearance of your eyes for 1 minute.</li>
        </ul>
        If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its 1-minute effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Vampiric Touch</name>
      <type>3rd-level necromancy</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Warlock</class>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>Self</range>
      <components>V, S</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
        The touch of your shadow-wreathed hand can siphon life force from others to heal your wounds. Make a melee spell attack against a creature within your reach. On a hit, the target takes 3d6 necrotic damage, and you regain hit points equal to half the amount of necrotic damage dealt. Until the spell ends, you can make the attack again on each of your turns as an action.<br/>
        <b>At Higher Levels.</b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.
      </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
      <name>Wall of Force</name>
      <type>5th-level evocation</type>
      <classes>
        <class>Wizard</class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime>1 action</castingTime>
      <range>120 feet</range>
      <components>V, S, M (a pinch of powder made by crushing a clear gemstone)</components>
      <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <description>
        An invisible wall of force springs into existence at a point you choose within range. The wall appears in any orientation you choose, as a horizontal or vertical barrier or at an angle. It can be free floating or resting on a solid surface. You can form it into a hemispherical dome or a sphere with a radius of up to 10 feet, or you can shape a flat surface made up of ten 10-foot-by- 10-foot panels. Each panel must be contiguous with another panel. In any form, the wall is 1/4 inch thick.<br/>
        It lasts for the duration. If the wall cuts through a creature’s space when it appears, the creature is pushed to one side of the wall (your choice which side).<br/>
        Nothing can physically pass through the wall. It is immune to all damage and can’t be dispelled by dispel magic. A disintegrate spell destroys the wall instantly, however. The wall also extends into the Ethereal Plane, blocking ethereal travel through the wall.
      </description>
    </spell>

  <!--
    <spell>
      <name></name>
      <type></type>
      <classes>
        <class></class>
      </classes>
      <castingTime></castingTime>
      <range></range>
      <components></components>
      <duration></duration>
      <shortDescription>
      </shortDescription>
      <atHigherLevel></atHigherLevel>
      <description>
      </description>
    </spell>

  -->
  </spells>
</cards>
